Joey?
喬伊？
Oh, my God.
喔，我的天啊！
Okay.
我答應你
So..
那麼…
I guess we should make it official, huh?
我想我們應該要正式點，對吧？
Look, Rach, I..
聽著，瑞秋，我…
Hey, Ross is here! Hey, look, it's my good friend Ross!
嘿，羅斯來了！ 嘿，瞧我的好朋友羅斯來了！
- Hey, Ross. - Hey, Joey.
-嘿，羅斯 -嘿，喬伊
- Hey, you. - Hey, you.
-嘿，你好 -嘿，你好
And he brought flowers! Thanks, Ross. I'm really more of a candy kind of guy.
還有花耶！謝了，羅斯 我是那種比較會送糖果的人
You're weird today.
你今天真詭異
Listen, I wanted to talk to you about something.
我有事想跟你談
Yeah. Actually, I kind of need to talk to you too.
事實上，我也需要跟你談談
- Joey, could you give us a minute? - No.
-喬伊，你可以迴避一下嗎？ -辦不到
- What? - I'm sorry. I meant, "No."
-什麼？ -我很抱歉，我是說做不到
Hi. Hey, look who's here.
嘿，瞧瞧誰來了
Where's my granddaughter? I've been practicing my magic tricks.
我的孫女在哪呢？ 我一直在練習變魔術
He pulled a quarter out of my ear.
他從我耳後變出一個銅板
- Hey, where's Mom? - She went to pick up Aunt Liddy.
-嘿，媽呢？ -她去接莉蒂阿姨
Aunt Liddy's coming? That means we get $5 each!
莉蒂阿姨要來？ 那我們又可以有錢拿囉！
So when do I get to meet Emma and show her this:
我何時才可以見到艾□ 然後表演這個給她看呢？
Okay, wow.
好耶，哇
Emma's in the nursery. I'll take you now if you want.
艾□在育嬰室 如果你要，我現在就帶你去
- But I really want to talk to you. - I know. I still need to talk to you.
-但是我真的想要跟你談談 -我知道，我也要跟你談談
But before you guys do that, I need to talk to you.
但是在你們談之前 我需要跟你談談
And Ross, I need to talk to you.
還有羅斯，我需要跟你談談
- And I need to talk to you. - About what?
-而我需要跟你談談 -談什麼？
To see if you know what these guys are talking about.
看你知不知道他們是要談什麼
The One Where No One Proposes
本集播出：求婚
rainystar壓制iPod-MP4
Isn't she beautiful?
她真是漂亮
Look at her, my first grandchild.
瞧瞧她，我第一個孫子
What about Ben?
那班算什麼？
Well, of course, Ben. I meant my first granddaughter.
喔，班，當然也是 我指的是我的第一個孫女
God, isn't she beautiful? Doesn't she look just like Rachel?
天啊，她真是漂亮 她看起來好像瑞秋，是吧？
I know everybody keeps saying that, but all I see is Vin Diesel.
我知道大家都一直這樣說 但是我倒覺得是像馮迪索
What do you think our baby will look like?
你覺得我們的小孩會像誰？
Oh, God. Please. You.
喔，天啊，拜託，要像你
But it'll have my sense of humor.
但是他會有我的絕佳幽默
Have you thought any more about you and Rachel?
你有想過跟瑞秋之間的可能性嗎？
Yeah, actually I was gonna talk to her when you guys came in the room.
有啊…事實上當你們進來時 我本來正要問她
Yeah, That's so exciting! Wow. You could've done that with us there.
真是太好了！哇 即使我們在，你也可以開口啊
- Yeah, right. - Sure. Okay.
-是啊，沒錯 -當然，是啊
You can touch yourself in front of us, but you can't talk to Rachel.
你能在我們面前自摸 卻不能在我們面前跟瑞秋談
What? When have I ever touched myself in front of you guys?
什麼？我何時在你們面前摸過我自己？
Oh, please. Just before, when you were asleep in the lounge.
喔，拜託，就在不久前 當你在客廳睡著時
That Armenian family was watching you instead of the TV.
那些亞美尼亞人都不看電視 反而在看你
That reminds me. That Mr. Hazmegian still has my Game Boy.
這倒提醒了我 我的任天堂還在賀斯梅先生那裡
- Chandler, can I talk to you for a second? - Sure.
-錢德，我可以跟你談一下嗎？ -當然
Dude, I just did something terrible.
兄弟，我剛做了一件很糟糕的事
That was you? I thought it was Jack.
原來是你做的，我以為是傑克
No, no. That was Jack. Rachel thinks I asked her to marry me.
不，那件事是傑克干的 瑞秋以為我跟她求婚
- What? Why does she think that? - Because it kind of looked like I did.
-什麼？她為什麼會那樣以為呢？ -因為看起來好像是我跟她求婚了
Again, what?
再說一次，什麼？
Okay, I was down on one knee with the ring in my hand..
好啦，我單膝跪在地上 手中拿著戒指…
As we all are at some point during the day.
像每個男人在一天當中 的某個時候都會做的
It wasn't my ring. It fell out of Ross' jacket..
那不是我的戒指 是從羅斯的夾克掉出來的
and when I knelt down to pick it up, Rachel thought I was proposing.
然後當我蹲下去要把它撿起來時 瑞秋以為我是在求婚
Ross had a ring? And he was gonna propose?
羅斯準備了戒指？ 他要求婚？
- I guess. - And you did it first?
-我想是吧 -而你搶在他之前先做了？
This is gonna kill him. You know how much he loves to propose.
他會很不爽的 你明知道他有多愛求婚這檔事
I know. I know. It's awful.
我知道，這真是太糟糕了
Well, what did she say?
那她怎麼回答呢？
She said, "Yes."
她答應了
You're smiling.
你在微笑
No, I'm not.
我沒有
Yes, you are. I can tell by the way your mouth is.
你有，我從你的嘴型就可以看出來
Does Ross know?
羅斯知道嗎？
Oh, my God. What the hell am I gonna tell him?
喔，我的天啊 我該怎麼告訴他呢？
- Maybe you don't have to tell him. - I like that. Yeah.
-或許你根本不用告訴他 -正合我意
If you clear things up with Rachel, Ross never needs to find out.
如果你先去跟瑞秋解釋清楚 羅斯就永遠不需要知道了
But you have to do it before he hears about it and kicks your ass.
但你必須在他發現而痛扁你之前 趕快行動
All right, let's not get carried away.
好吧，我們不要分心了
I want a baby.
我想要個小孩
Honey, we've been over this. I need to be facing the other way.
親愛的，我們已經討論過了 我必須要先轉過來才行
If we have sex again, it'll double our chances of getting pregnant.
如果我們再做愛 那我懷孕的機率就會增加一倍
- I think that closet's still available. - I am so tired.
-我想那間更衣室現在還是沒有人 -我好累喔
- Yeah, okay, but no foreplay. - Deal!
-好啦，但是說好沒有前戲喔 -沒問題！
Dad, seriously!
爸，拜託
You know, you really should see someone about that.
你應該要找醫生檢查看看了
Noted.
知道了
I wanna go talk to Rachel for a minute. Are you gonna be okay alone for a bit?
我要去找瑞秋談談 你自己一個人在這裡沒問題吧
Are you kidding me? I could stay and look at her forever.
你在開玩笑嗎？ 我可以目不轉睛的看著她
Actually..
事實上…
- Hey. - Hi.
-嘿 -嗨
Are you all right?
你還好嗎？
- I think I just got engaged. - Oh, my God! He did it?
-我想我剛訂婚了 -喔，天啊！他求婚了
What? Did you know he was gonna ask me?
什麼？你知道他要求婚嗎？
Are you kidding? I'm, like, the one who talked him into it.
你在開玩笑嗎？ 我就是那個慫恿他的人
I like to think of myself as the puppet master of the group.
我喜歡當我們這群人的玩偶操縱大師
- And you really think this is a good idea? - I just talked him into it.
-你真認為這是個好主意嗎？ -我才剛慫恿了他
Don't tell me I have to do you too?
別連你也要我慫恿才行
- The puppet master gets tired, people. - Okay.
-玩偶操縱大師也是會累的，拜託 -好吧
I don't know. It just doesn't feel right.
我不知道，總覺得怪怪的
Why? You two are so meant to be together. Everybody thinks so.
為什麼？你們倆是注定要在一起的 大家都這麼認為
Really? Even Ross?
真的？即使羅斯也是這樣想？
Especially Ross.
羅斯更是這樣想
Hey, Phoebe. You know what? I'll come back later.
嘿，菲比 我等一下再回來
Wow. Kind of a full house here.
哇，這裡真是擁擠
I guess I'll just.. I'll come back.
我想，我等一下再回來
There he goes. Your fiance.
他走了，你的未婚夫
I guess so.
我想是啊
Although he does play with himself in his sleep.
不過他會在睡著的時候自摸
I can't say I'm surprised.
我一點也不驚訝
- Dad, what are you doing? - There are people in there having sex.
-爸，你在做什麼？ -有兩個人在裡面做愛
It can't be me. I'm standing right here.
不可能是我，我人站在這裡
- Wanna peek? - No!
-想要偷看嗎？ -不要！
Come on.
別這樣
You know what? I don't like you without Mom.
你知道嗎？ 我討厭媽不在你身邊
Come on.
走吧
We're not peeking?
我們不偷看嗎？
Well, I'm peeking.
我還是要偷看
Oh, my God!
喔，我的天啊！
Hello, sir. You know Monica.
您好，您認識摩妮卡的
- Hey, is it okay to come in? - Of course.
-嘿，可以進來嗎？ -當然可以
Joey, this ring, I.. It's beautiful. I love it.
喬伊，這個戒指，我… 真是太美了，我好喜歡
Yeah. Look, Rach, there's something I gotta tell you.
是啊，聽著，瑞秋 有件事我必須要告訴你
- Hey. - Hi.
-嘿 -嗨
- Are you ready to try nursing again? - Yeah. Hi, Emma.
-你準備好要再試餵母乳了嗎？ -是啊，嗨，艾□
Why do you think she won't take my breast?
你想她為什麼不吸我的奶呢？
It's all right. It takes babies a while to get it.
沒關係的 嬰兒需要一點時間適應
- But don't worry, it'll happen. - Okay.
-不過別擔心，她會吸的 -好吧
Okay, sweetie, you can do it. Just open up and put it in your mouth.
好的，甜心，你可以辦得到的 張開嘴巴，然後把它放到嘴裡
Dear Lord.
救命啊，上帝
- I'm sorry, honey, what were you saying? - Yeah, look, I think that..
-我很抱歉，親愛的，你剛說什麼？ -喔，對，聽著，我想…
Because, look! She's pulling away again.
因為，瞧，她又轉開了
Do you think my nipples are too big for her mouth?
會不會是我的乳頭 對她而言太大了呢？
She looks scared. Doesn't she look scared?
她像是被嚇到了 她看起來是不是像被嚇到了呢？
You know, I don't really know her.
你知道的，我跟她又不是很熟
Why don't we try massaging the breast to stimulate the flow?
我們試試看按摩胸部來刺激乳汁分泌
- Okay. - Are you kidding me?
-好的 -你在玩我嗎？
This is so frustrating. Why doesn't she want my breast?
真是好沮喪！ 她為什麼不喜歡我的奶呢？
I don't know! Maybe she's crazy!
我不知道！或許她發瘋了！
- Hey, wait up. - Hi.
-嘿，等一下 -嗨
Congratulations.
恭喜了
I didn't want to say anything in front of Joey. I didn't know if he knew.
我不想在喬伊面前說 我不知道他是否知道
What? That we had a baby? Now let's give him a little credit.
什麼？他不知道我們有了小孩嗎？ 我們別太低估他了
Although he did eat a piece of plastic fruit earlier.
雖然他在稍早才吃了一個塑膠水果
No, no, that you and Rachel are engaged.
不，我是說你跟瑞秋訂婚的事
- What? - Oh, it's a secret?
-什麼？ -喔，那是秘密嗎？
Goody. Yes! We haven't done the secret thing in a long time.
太棒了，我們很久都沒有 玩秘密遊戲了
No, Rachel and I are not engaged.
不，瑞秋跟我沒有訂婚
I think you are.
我想你們有
What are you talking about? Who told you that?
你在說什麼？誰跟你說的？
Rachel, your betrothed.
瑞秋，你的未婚妻
- We're not engaged. - Oh, that's right. It's a secret.
-我們沒有訂婚 -喔，沒錯，那是個秘密
Right, you are not engaged. I misunderstood her.
沒錯，你們沒有訂婚 我誤解她了
Phoebe, there is no secret, okay? I didn't propose.
菲比，沒有什麼秘密，好嗎？ 我沒有求婚
Are you lying?
你在說謊嗎？
Is this like that time you tried to convince us you were a doctor?
是不是又跟上次一樣 要騙我們你是醫生（博士）？
I am a doctor!
我的確是博士！
You know what? I'm just gonna go and talk to Rachel myself.
你知道嗎？我要自己去跟瑞秋談
All right. Well, me too.
好吧，我也是
- Well, should we wake her up? - No. No. Come on, let her sleep.
-要不要叫醒她？ -不，別這樣，讓她睡
- She's so exhausted. - And so engaged.
-她真的是累壞了 -而且真的是訂婚了
Oh, my God. She thinks we're engaged!
喔，我的天，她以為我們訂婚了！
Why? Why, why would she think we're engaged?
為什麼？她為什麼認為我們訂婚了呢？
Perhaps because you gave her an engagement ring?
或許是因為你給了她訂婚戒指嗎？
You know, Ross, doctors are supposed to be smart.
你知道的，羅斯 博士應該要是很聰明的
- I didn't give her that ring. - You didn't?
-我沒有給她那個戒指 -你沒有嗎？
- No! - So whose ring is it?
-沒有！ -那是誰的戒指呢？
It's mine.
是我的
- Is it an engagement ring? - Yes.
-那是訂婚戒指嗎？ -是啊
- But you didn't give it to her? - No.
-但是你並沒有拿給她？ -沒有
- But you were going to propose? - No!
-但你本來是要求婚的？ -不是！
I might be losing interest in this.
我可能對這件事沒興趣了
Look. Look, my mom gave me that ring..
聽著，我媽給我那個戒指…
because she wanted me to propose to Rachel.
是因為她要我跟瑞秋求婚
But all I wanted to do was see..
但是我只想要知道…
if she maybe, kind of wanted to start things up again.
她是否願意再重新開始
What beautiful lukewarm sentiment.
不冷不熱的情感可真是美好啊
I didn't want to rush into anything. It seemed like she didn't want to either.
我不想要衝動行事 看起來她也不想要那樣
But I don't understand how any of this happened.
但我不瞭解這是怎麼發生的
What, did she find the ring in my jacket, assume I was gonna propose..
是她在我夾克找到戒指 然後就認為我要求婚…
throw it on and just start telling people?
便急著戴上戒指，向大家宣佈嗎？
No, no. She said you actually proposed to her.
不，她說你有向她求婚
Well, I didn't! I didn't propose!
我沒有！我沒有求婚！
Unless..
除非…
Did I?
我有嗎？
I haven't slept in 40 hours and..
我已經四十個小時沒睡而…
It does sound like something I would do.
這聽起來的確像是我會做的事
Look, we can't stay in here forever.
聽著，我們不能永遠待在這裡
It's just, I still can't believe that my dad saw us having sex.
我只是不敢相信我爸看到我們在做愛
He didn't make it to one of my piano recitals, but this he sees!
我的鋼琴獨奏會他連一次也沒去 但他卻看到這個！
This is okay. We're all adults here. There's nothing to be ashamed of.
沒關係的，我們都是大人了 沒有什麼好害羞的
Now, let's put our underwear in our pockets and walk out the door.
現在，我們把內褲放到口袋裡 然後走出去
Hi, Dad.
嗨，爸
- I can still call you that, right? - Of course. I'll always be your dad.
-我還是可以叫你爸，對吧？ -當然，我永遠都是你爸
I just want you to know that what you witnessed in there, that wasn't for fun.
我只想讓你知道，你在那裡所看到的 並非為了好玩而已
- It wasn't fun? - Why, why, why would you..?
-不好玩嗎？ -為什麼，為什麼你…
Look, I just don't want you to think..
我只是不想讓你認為…
that we're animals who do it whenever we want.
我們像動物一樣 隨時愛怎麼做就怎麼做
Well, I don't think that.
我不會那樣想的
Before today, I never thought of you two having sex at all.
在今天之前，我從未想過你們會做愛
It was a simpler time.
還是以前較簡單
The truth is, Dad, we're trying.
事實是，爸，我們正在努力
To kill you.
要氣死你
Why, why, why would you..?
為什麼，為什麼你…
We're trying to have a baby.
我們正在努力要做人
- What? - Yeah, we're trying to get pregnant.
-什麼？ -是啊，我們正在努力要懷孕
Oh, my God, this is so exciting.
喔，我的天啊，這真是太好了
Well, get back in there! I'll guard the door!
那再進去裡面！我來看門！
That's okay, Dad, we can wait until later.
沒關係，爸，我們可以等
Whoa! I don't think so. Aren't you ovulating?
哇！我可不這麼認為 你不是正在排卵嗎？
Daddy!
爸！
You gotta get at it, princess.
你要把握時機，小公主
When your mother and I were trying to conceive you..
當你媽跟我試著要懷你的時候…
whenever she was ovulating, bam, we did it!
只要她在排卵，我們就做！
That's how I got my bad hip.
這就是為什麼我的臀部會不好
That's funny. This conversation's how I got the bullet hole in my head.
真好笑，這個對話就是關於 我的頭怎樣被一顆子彈穿過
This one time I had my knee on the sink, and your mother was..
有一次我把膝蓋放到洗手台上 而你媽…
Seriously, sir, my brains, all over the wall.
真的，我的腦漿全都噴到牆上了
I don't think we need to hear the specific positions you and Mom had.
我想我們不需要知道 你跟媽的特殊姿勢
You're right. This is about your positions.
沒錯，應該要討論 你們的姿勢才對
Now, what I saw in the closet is not the optimum position..
我剛在更衣室裡面看到的，並非…
for conceiving a child.
最佳受孕姿勢
- Although it might feel good. - I don't feel good right now.
-雖然那感覺可能會很棒 -我現在一點也感覺不出來
But pleasure is important, and it helps if the woman has an orgasm.
但是快感是很重要的 而且如果女人有高潮是會有幫助的
You up to the task, sailor?
你要接受任務了嗎？小子
Oh, my God..
喔，我的天…
- Hey. - Hey. Oh, I need to tell you something.
-嘿 -嘿，喔，我需要告訴你一件事
Well, now's a good time. I'm on my way to have my ears cut off.
現在就正是時候 我正要去把我的耳朵切掉
Joey asked me to marry him.
喬伊要我嫁給他
- What? - Joey proposed to me.
-什麼？ -喬伊向我求婚
- Is he crazy? You just had Ross' baby! - Well, I said yes.
-他瘋了嗎？你才剛生下羅斯的孩子！ -我答應了
What, are you crazy? You just had Ross' baby!
什麼？你瘋了嗎？ 你才剛生下羅斯的孩子！
I'm sensing you won't throw the shower?
我覺得你不會 幫我辦慶祝會了，是吧？
It's so inappropriate. No, it is worse than that. It is wrong.
這真是太不配了 不，這更糟，這是不對的
It is bigger than mine!
而且比我的還大！
I know. Days of our Lives, thank you very much.
我知道，《我們的日子》 真是太感謝電視了
- You can't marry him. - Why not?
-你不能嫁給他 -為什麼不能？
Come on, I don't want to do this alone, and he's such a sweet guy.
我不想要一個人苦撐 而且他是個好人
And he loves me so much.
而且他很愛我
Well, do you love him?
那你愛他嗎？
Sure.
當然
- Sure? - Yeah, I mean, whatever.
-當然？ -是啊，我是說，隨便啦
If you're worried about breaking his heart, it's still broken from the last time.
如果你擔心他會心碎 別擔心，從上次到現在他的心還是碎的
So really, you're just taking the already broken pieces..
所以，你只不過是把上次的碎片…
and breaking them into smaller, more manageable pieces.
再輾成更小的碎片而已 更好處理的碎片
Okay, forget that.
好吧，算了
Honey, the question is..
親愛的，問題是…
do you really want to marry Joey?
你是真的想嫁給喬伊嗎？
No.
不是
No, I don't.
不，我不想
Could you be a dear and go tell him?
你可以好心一點幫我去告訴他嗎？
You still haven't told Rachel you weren't proposing?
你還沒有告訴瑞秋 你不是在求婚？
No. She had the ring on..
還沒有，她戴上了戒指…
she seemed so excited, and then she took her breast out.
她看起來很興奮 然後她露出胸部
Joey, you have to tell her what's going on. And what did it look like?
喬伊，你得要告訴她事實真相 胸部看起來怎樣？
I didn't look at it.
我沒有看到
The stupid baby's head was blocking most of it.
被那笨小孩的頭擋住了
Go and tell Rachel right now, before Ross finds out.
在羅斯發現之前，馬上去跟瑞秋說
Look, it's not that easy. She said she wanted to marry me.
聽著，事情沒那麼簡單 她說她想要嫁給我
I don't want to hurt her.
我不想要傷害她
Okay, look, just do it gently.
好啦，聽著，反正就是溫和地告訴她
You're right.
你說的沒錯
You're right. I'll go tell her now before Ross finds out, and I'll be gentle.
沒錯，我得在羅斯知道之前趕快告訴她 我會溫和地告訴她
I can do that. I am a gentle person.
我辦得到的，我是個溫和的人
By the way, two people screwing in there if you want to check that out.
對了，有兩個人在那裡面胡搞 你可以瞧瞧
Hey.
嘿
Listen, I heard about the engagement.
我聽說訂婚的事了
Surprised?
驚訝吧？
And confused.
而且很困惑
Rach, sweetie..
瑞秋，甜心…
I didn't propose to you.
我沒有向你求婚
I know.
我知道
I don't think you do.
我想你不知道
You didn't propose to me.
你沒有向我求婚
Joey did.
是喬伊向我求婚
Poor baby, you're so tired.
可憐的寶貝，你累壞了
Rach, I didn't propose to you.
瑞秋，我沒有向你求婚
Joey didn't propose to you.
喬伊沒有向你求婚
And Chandler didn't propose to you.
錢德也沒有向你求婚
You didn't propose to me.
你沒有向我求婚
Chandler didn't propose to me.
錢德沒有向我求婚
But Joey did.
但是喬伊有
Joey proposed to you?
喬伊跟你求婚？
- I can come back. - Wait. Wait. Wait.
-我可以等一下再回來 -等一下，等一下
- Joey, did you propose to her? - No.
-喬伊，你有跟她求婚嗎？ -沒有
- Yes, you did. - Actually, technically, I didn't.
-你有 -事實上，技術上而言，我沒有
- Well, then, why did you give me a ring? - Wait.
-那你為什麼給我戒指呢？ -等一下
- You gave her the ring? - No, and I did not ask her to marry me.
-你給她戒指？ -沒有，而且我也沒向她求婚
- Yes, you did. - No, I didn't.
-有，你有 -不，我沒有
-你有 -我沒有
Yes, you did, and don't you say you didn't!
你有，別再說你沒有了！
He was right there. He got down on one knee and he proposed.
他就在這裡，單膝跪下來 然後跟我求婚
- You were down on one knee? - Yeah, that looks bad.
-你跪了下去？ -是啊，看來真慘
But I didn't propose.
但是我並沒有求婚
- Then what did happen? - Yeah, what did happen?
-那到底是怎麼回事？ -是啊，到底是怎麼回事？
Okay, the ring fell on the floor, and I went down to pick it up..
是這樣的，戒指掉到了地上 然後我蹲下去撿…
and you thought I was proposing.
然後你就以為我是在求婚
Yeah, but you said, "Will you marry me?"
但是你有說「嫁給我好嗎？」
- No, I didn't. - Yes, you did.
-不，我沒說 -有，你有
- No, I didn't. - Yes, you did. Oh, my God, you didn't.
-不，我沒有 -有，你有，喔，天啊！你並沒有
- Why didn't you tell me that before? - Well, I tried..
-你為什麼不早點說呢？ -我有試著…
but people kept coming in, and then you took your breast out.
但是一直有人打斷 然後你又露出胸部
You saw her breast?
你看到她的胸部了？
I'll tell you about it later. Be cool.
我待會再告訴你，冷靜點
Then what the hell were you doing with an engagement ring?
那你拿個戒指幹什麼呢？
It wasn't my ring! It's Ross' ring.
那不是我的戒指！是羅斯的
That's why I felt so bad, Rach, because he was gonna propose.
這就是為什麼我好難過，瑞秋 因為本來是他要求婚的
What?!
什麼？
You were gonna propose to me?
你本來要跟我求婚？
No.
沒有
Well, this is awkward.
喔，這真是尷尬
But I was going to see if, you know, maybe you wanted to start dating again.
但是我本來是要問你 是否願意再重新開始約會
- But that, I mean, that was all, Rach. - Dude, step up. I proposed.
-但是，我是說，只不過是這樣，瑞秋 -老兄，加點油吧，我都求婚了
No, you didn't.
不，你沒有
That's right. There's a lot going on here, and I think I ate some bad fruit earlier.
沒錯，發生太多事了 我想我一定是吃了什麼壞掉的水果
All right, so let me just get this clear.
好了，讓我把事情搞清楚
You didn't propose.
你沒有求婚
You weren't gonna propose.
你也沒有要求婚
So this morning, I didn't have a boyfriend..
所以今天早上，我沒有男朋友…
and somehow I got dumped twice today.
然而卻被拋棄了兩次
Hey, she just woke up. She's hungry. Why don't we give this another try?
嘿，她剛醒來，而且餓了 我們再來試試看吧
Here we go again.
好戲又來啦
I can't believe you told her I was gonna propose.
我不敢相信你竟然告訴她我要求婚
- I can't believe you're not gonna. - Hey, I am not gonna rush into anything.
-我不敢相信你並沒有要求婚 -嘿，我不想要急著做什麼
Yeah, dude, I totally understand.
是啊，老兄，我完全可以理解
Usually after I have a baby with a woman, I like to slow things down!
通常在我跟一個女人生了小孩之後 我也會想要放慢腳步的
- Oh, my God! - What?
-喔，天啊！ -怎樣？
She's doing it! She's breast-feeding!
她在吸了！ 她在吸奶了！
It's beautiful.
真是太美妙了
- I'll come back for her later. - Thank you.
-我等一下再回來 -謝謝
- Wow, this feels weird. - What, good weird?
-哇，感覺真奇怪 -怎樣，是好的奇怪嗎？
Wonderful weird.
棒透了的奇怪
You know what, you guys? I'm gonna go too.
你們知道嗎？我也要走了
And I'm sorry about everything.
我很抱歉
- Honey, don't worry, it was my mistake. - No, Rach, I should've told you sooner.
-親愛的，別擔心，是我的錯 -不，瑞秋，我應該早點告訴你的
It's just that..
只不過…
Man, that kid is going to town!
天啊，這小孩真是厲害啊！
She's perfect.
她真是完美
We're so lucky.
我們真幸運
We really are.
我們真的很幸運
Look, I know it's not a proposal, and I don't know where you are..
聽著，我知道這不是求婚 而且我也不知道你的意思如何…
but with everything that's been going on and with Emma, I'm..
但是有了艾□之後 一切的事，我…
- I've been feeling.. - Yeah, I know.
-我一直感到… -是的，我知道
I've been feeling..
我一直感到…
- Yeah? - Yeah.
-是嗎？ -是啊
Okay, well, that.. Wow, okay, well..
好的，那麼，那… 哇，好的，那麼…
Then maybe at least we can talk about us again?
那麼或許我們可以再考慮在一起？
Yeah. Maybe.
是啊，或許
Well, good. Okay.
那，很好，好的
I kind of think, you know, if we, if..
我有點想，你知道的 如果我們，如果…
You're wearing the ring.
你手上戴著戒指
What's that?
你說什麼？
And you told Phoebe you were engaged.
你告訴菲比你訂婚了
I'm sorry, what?
很抱歉，你說什麼？
When you thought Joey proposed..
當你以為喬伊是在求婚…
did you say yes?
你有答應嗎？
Kids, I spoke to a doctor and picked up these pamphlets on how to get pregnant.
孩子們，我跟醫生談過 拿了這些懷孕須知的傳單給你們
- Hey, Dad. - Hi.
-嗨，爸 -嗨
Sorry to bother you again, but could you pass my pamphlets back?
很抱歉再打擾你們 但是可不可以把我的傳單遞出來呢？
Thank you.
謝謝